Sibusiso Sithole **Diploma in Systems Development**

Mobile: 067 947 4647 | Email: sibusisosithole765@gmail.com

Residential Area: Brakpan, Johannesburg | LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/sibusiso-sithole-

040404ss

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A dedicated and detail-orientated Software Development graduate from Gauteng City College, with a strong foundation in programming, software engineering principles, and data structures. My academic experience provided me with a comprehensive understanding of the following technical skills:

- JavaScript (5months) developed a working understanding of JavaScript concepts and syntax
- Python (6 months) engaged with python as part of learning to code using resources to understand basic programming principles
- HTML (12 months) involved in work during my undergraduate and internship
- CSS (8 months) gained experience with CSS for styling web interfaces, including using CSS frameworks like Material UI

I have a solid theoretical and practical understanding of development languages, supported by a strong foundation in logical thinking and quantitative analysis. I apply these skills effectively in designing and developing ground breaking software solutions. Additionally with my creative mindset and a passion for continuous learning, I am currently enhancing my technical expertise by completing JavaScript basic algorithms and web development fundamentals on Freedcodecamp as well as React Js Fundamentals on **Alison**

WORK EXPERIENCE

Job shadowing Spur Lakeside Mall (March 2015- March 2015)

Overview: I job shadowed at Spur Lakeside Mall a well-known family restaurant as part of a school assignment to expose us into level entry jobs, I had to assist and job shadow a waiter/waitress and understand their way of working as a form of experience.

Key Responsibilities

- Worked closely with kitchen and bar staff to ensure smooth services.
- Monitored order progress and ensured timely delivery to tables
- Present bills, accept payments, and give accurate change
- Greet guests warmly and ensure a pleasant dining experience

Volunteer | Tsakane Secondary (November 2019)

Overview: This was an initiative that I took to try and get some experience in the education sector, it is an unofficial step towards getting experience without receiving an incentive.

Key Responsibilities

- Assisted in administrative duties as per instructions such as filing and the preparation of study material.
- Ensured the distribution of school communications between the teacher and the students
- Collaborated in the compiling of past papers and academic activities

Intern Designer | Gods Followers Ministry October 2021- November 2022)

Overview: My role involved creating visually appealing

and organized church programmes. I also designed event posters that were eye catching and effectively conveyed key details of the event

Key Responsibilities

- Gained exposure to web content management and digital strategy through the coordination of online event promotions
- Designed visually engaging digital content for the church, such as posters and church programs
- Responsible for the management of the church's social media presence (primarily Facebook)

EDUCATION | QUALIFICATION

2020 - 2023: Diploma (Systems Development) | Gauteng City College

- I completed and I graduated with all the requirements for my diploma in Systems Development
- I successfully passed all my core modules that included Intro to Programming, Computer Architecture,
 Database Management Systems, and Computer Packages.

2014 - 2019: National Senior Certificate Nigel High School

 Completed subjects: Life Sciences (40) English Home Language (50), Afrikaans First Additional Language (40), Business Studies (62) Life Orientation (53), History (50), Mathematical Literacy(70)

COMPETENCIES AND SKILLS 999 Change according to the requirements

- Aspiring leader
- Communication
- Conflict management
- Curious
- Decision maker
- Energetic
- Problem solving
- High levels of adaptability
- Resilient
- Teamwork

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite (Word ,Excel , PowerPoint)
- Google Workspace
- Email Management
- Git
- Github
- React Js
- Angular
- Material UI
- Internet Proficiency